You've probably had
the opportunity to taste
the unparalleled flavor and
texture of "The Colony" honey.
Today we tell you about
its origins and mysteries.
In the south of Chile...
in the midst of an untamed wilderness...
framed by mountains of imposing beauty...
we live, we work, we serve
the community and we sing...
a group of German people.
To sing is our joy, to live.
Our motto: "Helping makes Happiness."
We choose to live close to nature...
...and secluded from the
tempations of the outside world.
In this way we feel we can
cultivate our hearts...
and live the way human beings
were truly meant to live on this earth.
The dark legend that has been created
around us is mainly due to ignorance.
They are ignorants those who fear a
community that remains isolated and pure.
Although we are a closed sanctuary we
pride ourselves on our strong connection...
we have with the Chilean
peasants that live near us.
Because they consider us Germans as their
brothers and their partners in hardship.
With the desire to communicate
a part of the many things...
this Society hopes to give to the
community and to our Chilean friends...
...we share with you this film rescued
from the vaults of our colony.
As shepherd of this community
I hope to dispel the horrible rumours
...that have stained our reputation.
I hope you will learn to appreciate
our colony just a little bit more.
This film was restored thanks to the collaboration
of Cristóbal León and Joaquín Cociña..
...and to the financial support
of the Government of Chile.
Once upon a time, a beautiful girl
named Maria lived in our Community.
Maria spent her time dreaming and playing
with the animals, instead of working.
One day Maria was disobedient and let
three pigs scape from their pen.
"You will spend a hundred days and a
hundred nights without talking to anyone..."
"so that you may reflect on what
you have done," we told her.
"It's not fair," Maria thought,
"I don't want anyone to tell me what to do"
So one night, when everyone was asleep,
Maria escaped from the Colony.
She ran into the woods alone
searching for a place to hide...
The wolf is coming.
He's near...
I can hear his breath.
The wolf is coming.
But he will not catch me.
Hello.
Is anybody here?
Is there a Chilean here?
Excuse me...
I need help.
I come from the colony.
There's a wolf outside.
Hello?
I need a shelter.
If you had a bit of water...
a bit of food...
I'd be very grateful.
If you could just help me.
Is anybody here?
Don't tell on me.
I am good.
Does anybody live here?
Please...
I'm really scared.
Don't say anything to the wolf.
Hello.
Ssshhh...
Don't be frightened...
I told them.
You two are so brave!
How did you escape the wolf?
Don't worry about me.
I don’t want to eat you.
Really...
I swear.
I told them I was not like the wolf...
that we were already safe...
that we were going to have our home.
To calm them down.
You have to rest and eat to be strong,
I told them.
I'm here now.
And they kind of understood.
Sleep, my child, sleep...
We will be able to...
...just relax.
We will be able to sit down...
...quietly.
I don't miss anyone.
Here I can play and sing.
I will transform my little pigs
into beautiful creatures...
that will never leave me.
A magic ball will help me
and no one will punish me.
Maria is here.
She looks so happy and
calm building her home.
Maria...
My beautiful little bird.
Do you feel me?
Do you hear me?
Maria...
I wish you were happy.
What is your house made of?
Did you close the doors and windows?
Remember...
that a stranger should
not enter into a real home.
A ball and a lamp...
tell me I can transform animals, beasts...
and human beings.
It's raining. It's raining.
The earth is getting wet.
The children are happy.
The grass is growing too.
It's raining. It's raining.
And when it has rained enough,
then it stops again.
It's raining. It's raining.
The earth is getting wet.
The children are happy.
Would you like to play...
...a little game I made up?
Change your hooves to hands.
Change your hooves to feet.
You'll see it's fun.
What's the name of my creatures?
Piggies with hands.
Piggies with feet.
They walk weird.
And they fall well.
When I was in the woods
running from the wolf...
...all of a sudden my eyes closed.
It was then that I saw
a little hole in a tree.
All of the animals of the forest
jumped into the little hole.
And I told myself:
“It’s eating them. Be careful!"
“It’s eating them!"
But no...
...the little animals laughed and fell in
happily like little breadcrumbs.
And flowers came out of the ground...
All around the tree...
And I knew they were the animals.
The tree thanked me for bringing
so many little animals.
I said, "You're welcome."
And the tree said:
“Maria, I'll give you a present
for your generosity.”
I woke up suddenly and I saw a red apple.
I ate it and I felt very good...
Like I had strength, a will to get up...
...a strength to create beautiful things
with my hands and my spirit.
I have a magical dress.
I gave them clothes for Christmas.
Christmas Eve.
Their black eyes were those of beasts.
They didn't talk or look smarter than pigs.
I told them my name was Maria.
A mother. An angel.
Maria is love and care.
From today you are Pedro and Ana.
Ana and Pedro.
I told them...
"I will teach you
everything I know."
"And you will be very good children."
"You will have no reason
to escape from here."
To the smaller pig I gave the name Pedro.
To the bigger pig, the name Ana.
I gave a name to both of them.
I gave them dignity.
Very deep.
There is Maria.
Working from sun to sun.
She has not rested in a long time.
She no longer sings.
She is sad.
My little bird.
Get some rest.
You have still so much to do.
What is your house made of?
The only way to be safe is to listen to me.
This is a tale called...
"The Dog and the House".
Once there was a dog who lived in a house.
He was a very naughty dog.
How bad he was.
The house would say to him,
"Dog… behave yourself."
"Dog…. Eat your food."
But the dog wouldn't listen.
It barked and bit all the time.
Despite all of that the house
loved him with all its heart.
And it protected him from all of the
dangers that plagued him in the forest.
The house loved the dog more
than anything in the world.
¨Don't ever run away little dog,
don't ever jump out the window"
"You might get lost and you won't be able
to find your way back."
The house would tell him.
But the little dog didn't listen and
he jumped out the window.
He laughed as he ran with all his might.
I'm not going to listen to the
nagging of this old house anymore.
The little doggy ran and ran...
And he went so far away that when
he wanted to return he didn’t know how.
Something very bad happened to him.
The wind brought back to the house
the smell of injuries and broken bones.
The house was very sad.
The days passed.
The nights passed.
But the little doggy never returned.
Poor house.
It wanted to do everything so well.
But the dog had been very disobedient.
And this is the end of the story, Pedrito.
I don't like to sleep.
I dream things.
I remember the other children
who lived with me.
I also remember the mountains
and the punishments.
And I wake up crying.
Ana and Pedro can't see me crying.
It isn't good.
Pedrito, Ana. You look so beautiful.
Do you know how to set the table?
Do you know what a table is?
Where do you put your arms, Ana?
How do you eat your soup, Pedro?
Sit up straight. Stay still.
Why do we make a toast today?
I understand that they don't answer.
But it makes me sad and angry
because of all the work.
I feel weak.
Oh no!
Be careful Pedrito!
You're burning!
Watch out Pedrito!
You're burning! Be careful.
The house is burning.
Maria...
Can you feel me my little bird?
-Can you hear me?
-Yes
-Do you know where I am?
-No
What is your new house made of Maria?
Is it fireproof?
I don't know.
Maria...
-Do you hear me my little bird?
-Yes
You burned the pigs!
What do you have to say
for yourself now Maria?
I didn't mean to!
You can't take care of the pigs!
But I can.
I know how to care for them.
You don't.
You think you can do
everything by yourself.
Let me in.
No
I don't want anymore punishments.
I was very harsh on Maria.
But it will be good for her.
Poor little bird.
Maria, Maria...
you were always a girl with a good heart.
It's not too late to fix things.
You have to work hard now.
Maria, Maria...
Dear Pedro...
You and Ana have been so brave.
You resisted the fire.
Soon you will get better.
Your skin darkened,
but your heart remains intact.
We are going to heal that skin.
All of the pain will pass.
Do you want to know
what this magic is called?
Listen well.
This magic is called honey.
Where I come from,
they hid it under the earth...
and chose who to give it to.
The dark-skinned children begged
him for it, but he didn't give it to them.
"They are dumb."
"They are lazy," he would say.
They punished me in a dark room.
There were many secret doors.
I wasn't allowed to cry.
Ana...
...sometimes her eyes are sad.
I’ve heard her sighs in the night...
...but Ana is and will be prettier.
I have to make yummy soup for her.
Clean the windows.
Clean the bandages...
so that she feels happy.
Ana
Little piggy.
She reminds me of a little newborn animal.
She can barely walk.
Sometimes her eyes are sad.
I’ve heard her sighs in the night...
Now rest Ana...
You will get better soon.
And so the time went by
in this house that hid some secrets...
like the sea, like an old treasure chest.
Maria closed all the windows and doors.
The only fun thing in the colony
were the pigs and the calves.
Sometimes I hid and imagined
that I was their mother.
Now the first thing I do
when I wake up is to dance.
And before sleeping I make jokes
to make Pedro and Ana laugh.
Now I can sleep a little.
I feel good.
I've known her since she
was still unable to walk.
She ate all the berries
and got her dress dirty.
I miss her.
Don't give up...
They can be better.
Pedro...
It’s time to decide...
if you want to become someone...
better...
stronger...
healthier...
bigger and more handsome...
Or if you want to stay small and ugly.
Drink this honey.
Well done Pedro. You chose well.
Look at you now.
You look so handsome now.
I'm so proud of you.
My dear Ana...
I’ll give you the gift of the voice.
So that every morning
you can name a flower.
In your hand that flower
that once was a stranger...
Will now be a gift
coming from your mouth.
Ana.
Everyone sleeps
peacefully in Maria's house.
Everyone is immersed in a sweet honey.
What does Ana dream about?
What does Pedro dream about?
They seem happy.
They try not to make a mess.
Ana says things like:
"Today I woke up happy."
"Then I helped Maria prepare dinner."
And also Pedro:
"Hi... me Pedro."
"Pedro, you must eat your food..."
...says Ana correctly.
And she keeps talking.
"I love you Pedro."
"Pedro loves me very much."
"He was born on Christmas night."
"Just like me."
It's sweet to hear her talk.
Pedro is smart.
"Dinner good..."
...he says.
He still speaks slow.
"We happy..."
...Pedro said.
Ana looks quiet.
She says...
"I feel free."
"The wolf is far away."
I hope she is right.
Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
Who has the fairest house of all?
Your house is fair...
...but there is one even fairer.
Look in your heart and you shall find it.
Why is my house not the fairest?
Why does the wolf say something like that?
He is jealous.
Bad.
I don't like him.
I don't need him.
I won't listen to him again.
Maria doesn't listen to me anymore.
But I know you do.
A long time passed.
Maria, Ana and Pedro
were a happy family.
But they hadn't been cautious.
I'm very hungry...
We'd eaten so little for weeks.
There were only a few things left...
...rotten things.
Stinking and sour.
I want something fresh.
I'm so hungry...
Hungry...
Maria eats too much.
Same rights.
Why privileges?
She's coming.
Bad.
In reality she's bad.
- Selfish.
- What were they whispering?
What are you eating?
I asked them.
Where did you keep that jam?
"We aren't eating anything, Maria..."
Ana lied to me...
with her mouth full.
"Nothing, nothing," Pedro said.
I didn't say anything.
I don't want to make them mad.
The hunger is getting inside of us.
Maybe the wolf is right...
This house wasn't safe all along.
I have to go find food.
The wolf knows how to get food...
The wolf knows the way back home...
Ana said to me...
"Where are you going?"
I explained that I was going
to pick apples in the woods.
Because we had no food.
"We’ve already spoken with Pedro."
Ana replied.
"Nobody can leave.
There is food here in the house."
"The wolf is outside."
Pedro also said no, that going out was bad.
"Go out bad."
Ana. Pedro.
I can hide from the wolf.
It is more important to get food.
But Ana and Pedro said...
"No, you can’t.
It’s dangerous to go out."
I see how they close the door behind them.
Ana and Pedro...
I no longer hear them breathing.
All of a sudden I feel a
tickling sensation...
...near my heart.
I try to look at my chest
but I'm tied up.
I can't breathe well.
I feel that I am very overwhelmed.
"Maria," Ana told me.
"You have to behave."
"Now that you're nervous..."
"you don't have to talk to us..."
"because if you talk to us,
you confuse us."
"We don't want to get confused."
I wanted to yell at them.
But I didn't dare.
I heard Pedro's voice...
"Hungry..."
"Hungry, hungry, hungry..."
"We're going to eat, Ana said."
Then I knew it wasn't a trick...
It wasn't a joke.
Dear wolf...
...I need you.
Wolf I beg you...
Please help me.
You were right.
You have to come.
Before they eat me.
Please huff and puff
and blow this house in.
Eat Pedro and Ana.
Don't let them eat me.
I need someone to take care of me,
permanently.
I can't do it alone.
Please come...
...and huff and puff
and blow this house in.
Huff and puff
And huff and puff
and erase your sadness.
and draw your smile.
It's me... I am here.
I have been here all along.
Inside of you.
I was always inside of you.
The whole time.
I eat...
I devour.
I swallow.
I eat...
Maria...
little bird...
It's time to go home.
Let's go.
And that is how this story ends.
Maria Wehrle was rescued
thanks to our incessant search.
In the colony she was able to
recover her vitality and helpful spirit.
She dedicates her days to the care of
children who come from different places in Chile...
to be educated and healed in the colony.
And you, little pig...
now that you have seen our dreams...
and your reflection on the water...
Do you want me to take care of you?